Guide to the A. P. Watt and Son records, 1861-1971 [bulk 1880-1949]
The New York Public Library. Henry W. and Albert A. Berg Collection of English and American Literature.
- Correspondence, 517474
  - Incoming Correspondence, 517493
    - Collier, Peter Fenelon. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1894 Mar. 13; 517568; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box (Haggard))
      With copies of 4 letters of related correspondence between C. J. Longman and C. J. Mills, Apr. 5 - May 15, 1894. Relate to Sir Henry Rider Haggard
    - Collins, Frances (Dunn). ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1880 Aug. 10; 517569; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
      Encloses list of works, 2 p.; and title page of Mortimer Collins' Thoughts in my garden, with her ms corrections
    - Collins, Frances (Dunn). ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1880 Aug. 19; 517570; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Collins, Frances (Dunn). ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1880 Aug. 26; 517571; in. corr.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box)
    - Collins, Frances (Dunn). ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1880 Oct. 6; 517572; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Cooper, Barbara. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y. Jan. 10; 517573; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Cooper, Katherine (Saunders). 6 ALS, 1 telegram to A. P. Watt and son, 1880 Aug. 7 - 1880 Oct. 7; 517574; in. corr.; 7 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
      With ms copy of telegram from Watt, Aug. 9, 1880. 1 p.
    - Corelli, Marie. 198 ALS, 17 ANS, 2 TLS, 8 telegrams to A. P. Watt and son, 1904 Oct. 12 - 1921 Dec. 31; 517575; in. corr.; 225 letters in 45 folders (Manuscript box)
      With letters to and from Corelli in folders 1, 2, 3, 4, 7, 10, 11, 21, and 22. See Guide to the Marie Corelli collection of papers, 1893-1955 bulk (1893-1945)
    - Cox, Anthony Berkeley. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1942 June 29; 517576; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Crandall, C[--?] F[--?]. 2 TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Rudyard Kipling, 1924 Oct. 1; 1924 Oct. 8; 517577; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box (Kipling))
      Letter of Oct. 1, 1924 encloses: Crandall, C. F. 2 TL (copies) to Rudyard Kipling. Sept. 26 and Oct. 1, 1924. 2 p.; 1 p. Kipling, Rudyard. TL (copy) to [C. F. Crandall] Sept. 29, 1924. 1 p.
    - Crauford, Alfred Lane. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Marie Corelli, 1896 Aug. 11; 1896 Aug. 13; 517578; in. corr.; 3 p.; 2 p (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - Crawford, David Alexander Robert Lindsay, 28th earl of. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1940 Apr. 23; 517579; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Crawshay-Williams, Eliot. ALS, TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 20; 1935 May 24; 517580; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
    - Creasey, C[--? H[--?] TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to H. G. Wells, 1929 June 22; 517581; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Wells))
    - Cripps, Sir Stafford. TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 1942 Jan. 29; 517582; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Crofts, Freeman Wills. ANS to [A. P. Watt and son], 1948 Dec. 18; 517583; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      With carbons of two related letters from Watt, Dec. 20, 1948. 1 p. each
    - Cronin, Archibald Joseph. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1937 Oct. 22; 517584; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Cunningham, A. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1914 Nov. 19; 517585; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Cust, Nina. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1914] Aug. 3; 517586; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - D'Abernon, Edgar Vincent, 1st viscount. TN to A. P. Watt and son, 1934 Mar. 2; 517587; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Signed with stamp
    - Daily Mail, London. TL to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to Morley Roberts, 1916 May 25; 517588; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Roberts, M.))
    - Dalrymple, Sir Charles Mark, 3rd bart. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 21; 517589; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Dawson, Geoffrey. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1941 Aug. 20; 517590; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Deans, Marjorie. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y.] Jan. 27; 517591; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - De la Mare, Walter. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1938 Sept. 12; 517592; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      With Watt's TL (carbon) reply. Accompanied by his: TL (copy) to Hellé Felcker. Aug. 24, 1938. 1 p. Relates to tuse of J. E. Flecker's poem Stillness in an anthology; with Flecker's Sept. 1, 1938 ALS to Watt & son and Watt's TL (carbon) reply
    - [De La Pasture, Edmé Elizabeth Monica]. 2 AN to A. P. Watt and son, 1929 Mar. 15; 1929 Apr. 6; 517593; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
      Signed Elizabeth M. Dashwood
    - Dell, Ethel May. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1919 Dec. 23; 517594; in. corr.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box)
    - Dennys, Joyce. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1936 June 24; 517595; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Dickens, Charles (1837-1896). ANS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to story by Jean Ingelow, 1880 Aug. 25; 517596; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Ingelow))
    - Dixey, Marmaduke L. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1936 Mar. 3; 517597; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Doran, firm, publishers, New York. TL (copy) to A. P. Watt & son. Relates to the Baroness Orczy, 1914 Mar. 9; 517598; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box (Orczy))
      With TL (copy) reply, April 9, 1914. 1 p.
    - Dorling, Henry Taprell. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1916 May 7; 517599; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Doubleday, Page & Co. 11 TL, 1 telegram to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Rudyard Kipling, 1923 Apr. 26 - 1941 Jan. 6; 517600; in. corr.; 12 letters in 4 folders (Manuscript box (Kipling))
      Signed Frank Nelson Doubleday, S. A. Everitt, et al...; With 6 TL (carbon) replies and 2 memoranda. Letter of July 17, 1935 encloses: [Kipling, Rudyard. A Kipling pageant] Foreword to the publisher [Nelson Doubleday]. Typescript, unsigned and undated. 5 p. Published Garden City, N.Y., Doubleday, Doran, 19
    - Doubleday, Page & Co. 23 TL, 1 TL (copy) and 8 telegrams to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to H. G. Wells, 1927 Sept. 2 - 1931 Sept. 22; 517601; in. corr.; 32 letters in 7 folders (Manuscript box (Wells))
      Signed George H. Doran and Nelson Doubleday. With carbons of 21 letters and 5 cables from Watt to Doubleday
    - Doyle, Adrian Conan. 3 ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Classic Comics edition of Sir A. C. Doyle's The Hound of the Baskervilles, 1943 Oct. 30 - 1944 May 12; 517602; in. corr.; 1 leaf each (Manuscript box (Doyle, A. C.))
      With 3 TL (carbon) replies; 2 TL, signed Arthur L. Kantor, from Gilberton Corp. to Watt, and TL (carbon) reply
    - Doyle, Arthur Conan, Sir. 6 ALS, 3 ANS (1 mutilated), 3 letters (signed for Doyle) to A. P. Watt and son, 1893 Oct.] - 1922 Feb. 24; 517603; in. corr.; 12 letters in 3 folders (Manuscript box)
      With ALS from Doyle's secretary, Charles Terry, to Watt, June 25 [1900] 1 p.; and 4 U.S. copyright office renewal forms for Doyle's books, 1924
    - Doyle, Denis Conan. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1931 Mar. 13; 1931 Mar. 16; 517604; in. corr.; 2 p.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Doyle, A. C.))
      With 6 TL (carbon) replies. Relate to National Broadcasting Company's use of Sir. A. C. Doyle's Sherlock Holmes stories
    - Doyle, Jean (Leckie), Lady. 10 TLS and 4 TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to use of Sir A. C. Doyle's stories by Leon M. Lion and the National Broadcasting Co., 1930 Sept. 27 - 1933 Jan. 30; 517605; in. corr.; 14 letters in 3 folders (Manuscript box (Doyle, A. C.))
      With 28 TL (carbon) replies
    - Dreadnought Productions, Ltd., Liverpool. 2 TN and 6 typed statements to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to film of Marie Corelli's Sorrows of Satan, 1917 Jan. 20 - 1918 Sept. 16; 517606; in. corr.; 8 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box (Corelli))
      2 TN signed C[--?] A[--?] Watson
    - Dugdale, Blanche Elizabeth Campbell (Balfour). 12 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 postcard to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to her biography of her uncle, Arthur James Balfour, 1st earl of Balfour, 1930 Apr. 4 - 1932 May 4; 517607; in. corr.; 14 letters in 3 folders (Manuscript box (Balfour))
      Letter of Feb. 14, 1932 encloses 2 draft agreements
    - Elliott, H[--?] B[--?]. ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to G. K. Chesterton and others, 1912 Nov. 25; 517608; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box (Chesterton))
    - Ellis, G[--?] U[--?]. TLS to [A. P. Watt and son], 1937 Mar. 31; 517609; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - English Illustrated Magazine. Letter to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to Stanley John Weyman, 1891 Mar. 17; 517610; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Weyman))
      Signed A[--?] G[--?] Gilbert
    - Eyre-Lloyd, [--?]. ALS to [A. P. Watt and son], 517611; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Fabulet, Louis. 22 ALS, 13 postcards to A. P. Watt & son. Relate to his translations of Rudyard Kipling, 1900 Feb. 7 - 1908 June 15; 517612; in. corr.; 35 letters in 7 folders (Manuscript box (Kipling))
      With TL (copy), translation only, of letter of April 18, 1906
    - Farjeon, Benjamin Leopold. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1902 Sept. 27; 1902 Oct. 21; 517613; in. corr.; 1 p.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Farnol, Jeffery. 4 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1927 Sept. 19 - 1930 Jan. 6; 517614; in. corr.; 1 p.; 2 p.; 1 p.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      With carbon of letter from Watt, Jan. 8, 1930
    - Field, Roscoe & Co., London. 53 TLS, 24 TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Marie Corelli, 1915 Apr. 14 - 1945 Feb. 21; 517615; in. corr.; 77 letters in 8 folders (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - Field, Roscoe & Co., London. 17 TL, 2 TN to A. P. Watt and son, 1921 Feb. 14 - 1933 Feb. 7; 517616; in. corr.; 19 letters in 4 folders (Manuscript box (Doyle, A. C.))
      2 TN signed C. D. Medley. With 7 TL (carbon) replies. Relate to use of Sir Arthur Conan Doyle's stories by Leon M. Lion and the National Broadcasting Co., etc.
    - Field, Roscoe & Co., London. 20 TL to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to E. W. Martindell's bibliography of Rudyard Kipling and to Canadian copyright infringements of Kipling's works, 1923 Nov. 28 - 1931 Sept. 29; 517617; in. corr.; 20 letters in 6 folders (Manuscript box (Kipling))
      Signed C. D. Medley. With 8 TL (carbon) replies and 7 related memoranda
    - Field, Roscoe & Co., London. 16 TL, 5 TN to A. P. Watt and son, 1927 May 16 - 1931 Oct. 20; 517618; in. corr.; 21 letters in 1 envelope ((Wells))
      Signed C. D. Medley. With 5 TL (carbon) replies and 5 documents relating to the Doran-Wells-Huxley corporation formed to publish The Science of Life
    - Field, Roscoe & Co., London. 7 TL, 5 TN to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Jeffery Farnol, 1927 June 11 - 1931 Apr. 28; 517619; in. corr.; 12 letters (Manuscript box (Farnol))
      With 6 TL (carbon) replies and 3 memoranda
    - Findlater, Jane Helen. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1905] Mar. 10; 517620; in. corr.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box)
    - Fisher, Margaret. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y.] July 22; 517621; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Flecker, Hellé. ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to film version of J. E. Flecker's Hassan, 1938 Sept. 1; 517622; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
      With Watt's TL (carbon) reply; also with De la Mare, Walter. TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Sept. 12, 1938
    - Fleming, Ian. 2 TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to William Somerset Maugham, 1954 May 14; 1954 May 24; 517623; in. corr.; 1 leaf; 1 p (Manuscript box (Maugham))
    - Frankau, Gilbert. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 21; 517624; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Frankau[?], Pamela. AL to A. P. Watt and son, 517625; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Signed "Pamela"
    - Freeman, Richard Austin. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 22; 517626; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      With 2 receipts from Chatto & Windus, Feb. 18, 1927
    - Garvice, Charles. ALS, 2 TLS, 2 TL (carbons) to A. P. Watt and son, 1910 Mar. 9 - 1919 Nov. 11; 517627; in. corr.; 5 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
      On versos of Nov. 7 and 11, 1919: typescript, paginated 2 and 10, from unidentified novels. With holograph quotation signed, 1 p. and TLS from Watt, Oct. 16, 1905, 1 p., with enclosure, 1 p.
    - Gaskell, Charles Milnes. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1936 Oct. 7; 517628; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Geikie, Cunningham. 5 ALS, 1 postcard to A. P. Watt and son, 1878 June 3 - 1880 June 8; 517629; in. corr.; 6 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
      With ms extract from letter to "L.D.C." [of A. P. Watt and son?], June 4, 1880, and two printed selections of reviewers' notices
    - Gielgud, Sir John. TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 1937 Oct. 30; 517630; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Gillette, William Hooker. 5 ALS, 3 telegrams to A. P. Watt and son. Letter of Sept. 5, 1887 annotated by Sir H. R. Haggard, 1887 Sept. 5 - 1887 Nov. 17; 517631; in. corr.; 8 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box)
      Enclosed in Nov. 17, 1887: Agreement (draft) between Sir Haggard and Gillette for dramatization of She. 1 p., with copy, 1 p.; From the files of A. P. Watt and son
    - Godber, Noël, TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1937 May 24; 517632; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Good Words. Letter to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to David Christie Murray, 1886 Oct. 25; 517633; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box (Murray, D. C.))
    - Gorell, Ronald Gorell Barnes, 3rd baron. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 17; 517634; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Gow, Ronald. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 23; 517635; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Graves, Robert. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1921] Apr. 3; 517636; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Graves, Robert. Postcard to A. P. Watt and son, 1921 Aug. 18; 517637; in. corr.; 1 card (Manuscript box)
    - Graves, Robert. ANS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to W. S. Maugham, 1947 Nov. 18; 517638; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Gregory, Isabella Augusta Persse, Lady. ALS (draft) to A. P. Watt and son, 1923] Apr. 16; 517639; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
      With reply from A. P. Watt, July 12, 1923. 1 p.; and with her ALS (copy) to Watt. Sept. 13, 1923. 1 leaf. Removed from: Gregory. Journal, vol. 23, p. 2100
    - Gurlitz, Augustus T. TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to law suit between Rudyard Kipling and G. P. Putnam's sons, 1901 Jan. 9; 517640; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box (Kipling))
      Encloses: Waugh, Arthur. [Affidavit in case of Rudyard Kipling v. G.P. Putnam's sons and others]. Typescript (carbon), unsigned, dated London, Nov. 16, 1900. 1 p.
    - Gurlitz, Augustus T. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1905 Nov. 17; 517641; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box (Corelli))
      With 17 items relating to the printing and copyright of Marie Corelli's Old-fashioned fidelity, including a copy of the story
    - Haggard, Sir Henry Rider. 25 ALS, 5 TLS, 3 LS, 8 miscellaneous pieces to A. P. Watt and son, 1885 Nov. 15 - 1920 Nov. 13; 517642; in. corr.; 41 letters in 8 folders (Manuscript box)
      With ms extract from Watt's letter to Haggard, May 13, 1887 and three ANS from haggard's secretary, Ida Hector, to Wattd
    - Hall, Evelyn Beatrice. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1902] Dec. 17; 517643; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hall, Evelyn Beatrice. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1908] Dec. 8; 517644; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hall, Evelyn Beatrice. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y. July 3; 517645; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hall, Evelyn Beatrice. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1930 Feb. 14; 517646; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Hall, James Norman. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 20; 517647; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hamilton, Lord Ernest William. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y.] Mar. 25; 517648; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
      Published in Letters to A. P. Watt and his sons, 1883-1924. London, 1924, p. 84
    - Hannay, James Owen. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 23; 517649; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hanson, Laurence. 5 ALS, 2 ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1940 Nov. 27 - 1941 Apr. 28; 517650; in. corr.; 7 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box (Kipling, R.))
      With 3 enclosures relating to Rudyard Kipling's books, and five TL (carbon) replies
    - Hardy, J[--?] L--?]. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 Apr. 18; 517651; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hardy, Thomas. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1891 Sept. 7; 517652; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Harraden, Beatrice. 3 ALS, 1 ANS, 1 LS to A. P. Watt and son, 1896] Nov. 25 - [1908] Dec. 6; 517653; in. corr.; 5 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
      With TLS from Watt, Sept. 3, 1895. 1 p.
    - Harte, Bret. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1886 Mar. 13; 517654; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Harwood, Sir Ralph. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1936 June 17; 517655; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hawkins, Sir Anthony Hope. 3 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1901 Jan. 9 - 1921 Oct. 2; 517656; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
      Letter of Oct. 2, 1921 encloses ALS printed in Letters to A. P. Watt and his sons 1883-1924. London, A. P. Watt & son, 1924, p. 100-101
    - Head, A[--?] M[--?]. TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Written as secretary to Lord Alfred Douglas, 1908 Apr. 28; 517657; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Douglas, A. B.))
    - Heinemann, William, Ltd., London. 6 TL, 1 TN to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to H. G. Wells, 1926 Nov. 4 - 1931 June 30; 517658; in. corr.; 7 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box (Wells))
      TL signed Charles Seddon Evans; TN signed Theodore Byard. With carbons of 12 letters from Watt to Heinemann
    - Henderson, Sir Nevile. ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1940 Jan. 7; 517659; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Henty, George Alfred. ALS, ANS to A. P. Watt and son. Letter of Aug. 23, 1881 relates to story by Jules Verne, 1880 Aug. 21; 1881 Aug. 23; 517660; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
    - Hewart, Gordon Hewart, 1st viscount. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 20; 517661; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hichens, Robert Smythe. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1905 Jan. 2; 517662; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hichens, Robert Smythe. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1905 Jan. 10; 517663; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hichens, Robert Smythe. ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1905 Jan. [12?; 517664; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hichens, Robert Smythe. ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 20; 517665; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hodder & Stoughton, firm, publishers, London. TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to E. A. M. Albanesi's copyrights, 1914 July 14; 517666; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Albanesi))
    - Hodder & Stoughton, firm, publishers, London. 4 TL to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to illustration of Rudyard Kipling's poems by Sir Frank Brangwyn, 1923 Nov. 9 - 1936 Mar. 12; 517667; in. corr.; 4 letters (Manuscript box (Kipling))
      Signed Ernest Hodder-Williams and Ralph Hodder-Williams. With 2 TL (carbon) replies and four memoranda. Accompanied by: Brangwyn, Sir Frank. TL (copy) to [Rudyard Kipling] [1924?] 1 p.; From the files of A. P. Watt and son
    - Hole, Samuel Reynolds. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1902 Jan. 10; 517668; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box (Kipling))
    - Holland, Constance. 4 TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Written as secretary to Lady Conan Doyle, 1932 Nov. 15 - 1933 Feb. 10; 517669; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box (Doyle, A. C.))
      With TL (carbon) reply, Sept. 23, 1931. 1 p.; Enclosed in Jan. 13, 1933: Lion, Leon M. 6 TL (copies) to Lady Leckie Doyle. Aug. 24-Dec. 29, 1932. Relate to play based on Sir A. C. Doyle's Sherlock Holmes
    - Horder, Thomas Jeeves Horder, baron. ALS to [A. P. Watt and son], 1935 Oct. 20; 517670; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
      With related letter from Hodder and Stoughton, Ltd. to Watt, Oct. 8, 1935
    - Horler, Sydney. 3 ALS, 1 TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 19 - 1939 Jan. 5; 517671; in. corr.; 4 letters (Manuscript box)
      With 2 related Watt memoranda, May 24, 1935
    - Housman, Laurence. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1941 June 28; 517672; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Humphreys, Eliza Margaret J. (Gollan). 2 AL to A. P. Watt and son, 1916 June 28; 1921 Apr. 9; 517673; in. corr.; 2 p.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
      With letter from her secretary to Watt, July 5, 1916. 2 p.
    - Humphreys, H[--?] R[--?]. ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1931 Sept. 25; 517674; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hunloke, Sir Philip. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1936 July 4; 517675; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Hunter, William. 11 ALS, 1 LS, 35 letters, and 3 telegrams to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to the sale of Strahan & co. publications, especially those of R. W. Buchanan, George MacDonald, C. J. Vaughan, and George Douglas Campbell, 8th duke of Argyll, 1886 May 18 - 1887 Dec. 1; 517676; in. corr.; 50 letters in 10 folders (Manuscript box (Watt, A. P.))
      35 letters signed for Hunter. With 38 pieces of related correspondence with various publishers, etc., and 16 miscellaneous pieces
    - Hunter, Rose & co., Toronto. 4 LS, 2 telegrams to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Canadian publication of Sir H. R. Haggard's Allan Quatermain, 1887 Apr. 16 - 1887 June 8; 517677; in. corr.; 6 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box (Haggard))
      With telegram to Longman and Co., London, March 14, 1887
    - Hutchinson, Graham Seton. TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 22; 517678; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Huxley, Aldous. ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 517679; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Written at bottom of Watt's TLS to Huxley, May 26, 1941; with TL (carbon) from Watt, Jan. 17, 1941
    - Huxley, Marie Juliette (Baillot). ANS to A. P. Watt and son. Written for her husband, Julian Sorell Huxley, who collaborated with H. G. Wells on The science of life, 1929] Sept. 6; 517680; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Wells))
      Accompanied by: Coombs, Phyllis M. TLS to A. P. Watt, Jan. 11, 1930. 1 p. Written as secretary to Julian Huxley. With carbons of three letters from Watt to Huxley
    - Incorporated Society of Authors, Playwrights and Composers, London. TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to Marie Corelli, 1915 Dec. 7; 517681; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - James, Henry (1843-1916). 2 ALS, 1 telegram (mutilated) to A. P. Watt and son, 1890 Apr. 2 - 1890 Apr. 9; 517682; in. corr.; 2 p.; 3 p. 1 letter (Manuscript box)
    - Jay, Harriett. 4 ALS, 3 telegrams to A. P. Watt and son, 1880 July 26 - 1881 Jan. 28; 517683; in. corr.; 7 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
    - Jenkins, Edward. 7 ALS, 9 ANS, 2 AN, 1 telegram to A. P. Watt and son, 1880?] Jan. 27 - 1881 Mar. 3; 517684; in. corr.; 19 letters in 4 folders (Manuscript box)
      With his holograph outline of proposed book on Hungary, 3 p., and copy, 3 p.
    - Jerome, Jerome Klapka. 2 ALS, 4 LS, 1 letter (copy) to A. P. Watt and son, 1904 Dec. 17 - 1923 Dec. 22; 517685; in. corr.; 7 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box)
      Letter of Sept. 26, 1914 encloses: The Daily Chronicle, London. TL, signed Robert Donald, to Jerome Klapka Jerome. July 30, 1914. 2 p. Relates to Today. With enclosures, 2 p. and ms copy of Jerome's reply, 2 p.
    - Johnston, Edith. 3 TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Charles Garvice and Charlotte Mary Brame, 1920 Apr. 19 - 1920 Dec. 20; 517686; in. corr.; 1 p.; 1 p.; 2 p (Manuscript box (Garvice))
      Letter of Dec. 20, 1920, encloses "First list of titles suitable for films," 1 p.; With related Watt memorandum, "Books [of Charles Garvice] sold for the films," 1 p.
    - Johnston, Sir Harry Hamilton. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1902 July 9; 1902 July 9; 517687; in. corr.; 1 leaf; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Kelly, Sir Gerald Festus. TLS, TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Letter of June7 quotes letter from William Somerset Maugham to Kelly, 1938 June 7; 1938 June 13; 517688; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
      With carbons of two letter from Watt and three related memoranda